Curriculum Vitae

Updated on 7/7/2020

Ibrahim O. Shanqiti Tel No. +971 55 1913121

Email: ibrahim.shanqiti@gmail.com - ibrahim@shanqt.com

Dubai, United Arab Emirates

Ibrahimshangiti.com

Education-Focused Channel

Summary:

All Rounded Student at Dubai International Academy in 11C. I speak two languages fluently, one being English and the other being my native language, Arabic. I like to consider myself a jack of all trades, especially in the tech-side of life, since I started actively using some sort of advanced technology/software or another when I was very young. I started learning Adobe Photoshop almost 6 years ago, and I've branched out to Sony Vegas Pro and After Effects meanwhile. The amalgamation of these skills are presented in the educational Youtube videos I produce, as well as my graphic design portfolio as a whole. I later began learning HTML, CSS and then eventually Python, all of which I consider myself at an intermediate level. I am highly proficient in almost all of my subjects, especially Mathematics, Physics & English. I've now been part of the DIAlect school newsletter club for three years, starting off as the lowest position, now reaching President. I thoroughly enjoy journalistic and creative writing. I am also an extremely powerful debater and Model United Nations delegate, achieving 5 best delegates in a row, while participating in 5 conferences. Eventually, I made my way up to my current position, Deputy Secretary General of the Middle East's biggest MUN conference, DIAMUN.

Academic History:

- **2008-2011** - KG 2 - Year 3

Al Mawakeb - Barsha:

California NGSS, California CCSSM, California CCSSE

- **2012 - 2020** - Year 4 - Year 11

Dubai International Academy - Emirates Hills:

International Baccalaureate Curriculum

Certifications:

- QPR Suicide Prevention Certified
- Deputy Heart Attack Course Certified
- PFA (Psychological First Aid) Course from NCTSN Certified
- FEMA Safety Travel Rules & Regulations Certified
- FEMA Active Shooter: What can you do Certified.

Experience:

Model United Nations:

- 5 Years experience of the After School Activity (Have assisted teaching)
- 2015 DIAMUN Conference Delegate
- 2018-2019 EISJ Conference (Best Delegate Award) Delegate
- 2018-2019 DIAMUN Conference (Best Delegate Award) Delegate
- 2019-2020 EISJ Conference (Best Delegate Award Security Council) Delegate
- 2020 DIAMUN Conference Chair (Conference cancelled, chair training only)
- 2020 IDMUNIII Online Conference (Outstanding Delegate Award) Delegate
- 2020 DPSDMUN EMUN Online Conference (Best Delegate Award) Delegate
- 2020 DIAMUN Online Conference Chair

Student Bodies:

- 1 Year as Student Council (2018-2019)
- 1 Year Reserve Deputy House Captain (House Air) (2019-2020)
- Helped organize and manage the 2019-2020 sports day.
- 1 Year Friendship Ambassador (2019-2020)

Online Courses:

- Introduction to Philosophy University of Edinburgh
- The Manager's Toolkit: A Practical Guide to Managing People at Work University of London (In Progress)

DIAlect (School Newspaper):

- Deputy Writer for the Mini-Howler (2018-2019)
- Head Writer for the News Society (International News) (2019-2020)
- Worked with the President to create "The DIAlect Podcast" (2019-2020)
- President & Editor-In-Chief of DIAlect (2020-2021)

DIAMUN (Dubai International Academy Model United Nations):

- Organized the DIAMUN 2020 Online Conference
- Deputy Secretary General of DIAMUN 2021
- Organized DIAMUN's first Crisis Committee in the form of the Historical Security Council Crisis Committee, in celebration of the United Nations 75th Anniversary.

Water for Life (Charity):

- Deputy Head of Media and Communications (2019-2020)
- Helped present and organize a charity event that would raise thousands of dollars for the GIVE foundation. (cancelled due to COVID-19).

Paradigm (Organization):

- Senior Partner
- Researching, Writing and Conducting podcast interviews regarding student life after graduating high school.

Duke of Edinburgh Award:

- Bronze Award (in development, Camping Trip has been passed)
- 2018 2019 Duke of Edinburgh Student Officer
- Silver Award (in development, Camping Trip has been passed)

Competitions:

- Business Minds Case Study Competition 2020
- Jane Austen Literacy Foundation Competition 2020
- Breakthrough Junior Challenge 2020

Skills:

- Technology: PC Building, Mac, Windows, hardware.
- Languages: Arabic (native), English (Fluent & Extreme proficiency)
- Microsoft Office Suite.
- Graphic Design: 6 Years using Photoshop, Illustrator (basic).
- Video Editing: 4 Years using After Effects and Sony Vegas Pro. Adobe Premiere Pro (basic).
- Instruments: Piano Grade 5 ABRSM, Intermediate Ukulele, Beginner Bass, Electric and Acoustic Guitar.
- Programming skills Python, HTML, CSS. Java, Wolfram Mathematica and LaTeX (basic).
- Advanced journalistic writing Wrote about events within the school community, as well as International News.
- Creative Writing I wrote a fictional novel for a school project, named "Murder in Noire".

Soft Skills:

- Excellent teamwork, work well in large and small groups.
- Superb leadership skills, as seen in my leadership positions.
- Very strong public speaking skills.
- Proficient in Debate.
- Outstanding communication skills.
- Works very well under pressure.
- Great helper to others and works well with other people.
- Adapts to foreign situations well.
- Experienced in conflict resolution.